Speier, Hans; Papers ger084
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Miscellaneous typescripts and publications by other authors, 1941-1982; 6; 85 file folders
  - Authored articles, 6.2
    - Westcott, Marcia. "Conservative Method", 1975 November; typescript (Box 11 (6-Miscellaneous typescripts and publications by othe), Folder 78)
    - Wettig, Gerhard. "Der Dialog zwischen SPD und SED vom Februar bis Juni 1966 als Teil der Deutschlandpolitik des Ostblocks", 1966 December; mimeograph (Box 11 (6-Miscellaneous typescripts and publications by othe), Folder 79)
    - Wettig, Gerhard. "Soviet Non-Proliferation Policy: An Analysis of Soviet Public Statements from November 1966 to January 1968", 1968 July; bound typescript (Box 11 (6-Miscellaneous typescripts and publications by othe), Folder 80)
    - Whaley, Barton. "Soviet Clandestine Communications Net. Notes for a History of the Structures of the Intelligence Services of the USSR", 1969 September; bound typescript (Box 11 (6-Miscellaneous typescripts and publications by othe), Folder 81)
    - White, Howard, Undated (Box 11 (6-Miscellaneous typescripts and publications by othe), Folder 82)
      "Ghost Voices". Typescript, April 1943; "The Political Philosophy of Shakespeare". Mimeo, undated.
    - White, Howard B., Undated (Box 11 (6-Miscellaneous typescripts and publications by othe), Folder 83)
      "The Problem of Loyalty in American Political Thought". Reprint, Autumn 1954; "The Loyalty of Oath". Reprint, Spring 1955.
    - Wohlstetter, Albert and Roberta. "Controlling the Risks in Cuba", 1955 April; photocopy (Box 11 (6-Miscellaneous typescripts and publications by othe), Folder 84)
    - Zoppo, Ciro Elliott. "Nuclear Technology, Multipolarity, and International Stability", 1966 July; reprint (Box 11 (6-Miscellaneous typescripts and publications by othe), Folder 85)
- Nazi and anti-Nazi propaganda, 7; 75 file folders and 1 scrapbook
  Nazi propaganda, 1941-1944; Anti-Nazi propaganda, 1943-1944; Allied Forces Intelligence Reports and memoranda, 1940-1948.
  This series contains both Nazi propaganda, disseminated by the Reichspropagandaamt in Berlin, as well as anti-Nazi propaganda, disseminated by the Psychological Warfare Branch of the U.S. Army, 1943-1944. The Anti-Nazi propaganda collection consists of ca. 220 individual leaflets and one scrapbook containing leaflets, which were disseminated by shell-fire and by artillery observation planes over enemy troops on the Fifth Army front during the Italian campaign. Also contained in this series are intelligence reports and memoranda from the Allied Forces Psychological Warfare Section and the Information Control Division, as well as War Office memoranda.
  - Nazi propaganda, 1941-1944; 7.1
    - Zeitschriften-Dienst, 1941-1942 (Box 12 (7-Nazi and anti-Nazi propaganda), Folder 1)
      Newspaper issues.
    - Mimeographed publications of the Reichspropagandaamt, Berlin, 1941 (Box 12 (7-Nazi and anti-Nazi propaganda), Folder 2)
    - Mimeographed publications of the Reichspropagandaamt, Berlin, 1942 (Box 12 (7-Nazi and anti-Nazi propaganda), Folder 3)
    - Mimeographed publications of the Reichspropagandaamt, Berlin, 1943 (Box 12 (7-Nazi and anti-Nazi propaganda), Folder 4)
    - Mimeographed publications of the Reichspropagandaamt, Berlin, 1944 (Box 12 (7-Nazi and anti-Nazi propaganda), Folder 5)
    - Allied Forces reports, 1941-1944 (Box 12 (7-Nazi and anti-Nazi propaganda), Folder 5)
  - Weekly Analysis of Official Foreign Broadcasts, 1941-1942 (Box 12 (7-Nazi and anti-Nazi propaganda), Folder 6)
  - Office of War Information. Special Reports, 1942 (Box 12 (7-Nazi and anti-Nazi propaganda), Folder 7)
  - Federal Communications Commission, Foreign Broadcast Intelligence Service, Special Reports, 1942-1944 (Box 12 (7-Nazi and anti-Nazi propaganda), Folder 8-10)
  - Anti-Nazi propaganda scrapbook containing shell leaflets, 1943-1944 (Box 13A (7-Nazi and anti-Nazi propaganda), Folder 1)
  - Shell leaflets, individually numbered 1-227 (missing numbers 5, 34, 60-61, 73, 92, 161, 192), 1943-1944 (Box 13B (7-Nazi and anti-Nazi propaganda), Folder 1-60)
  - Allied Forces Psychological Warfare Section [[RESTRICTED]], 1945 (Box 13B (7-Nazi and anti-Nazi propaganda), Folder 61)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Must consult archivist before viewing this material.
  - Allied Forces Psychological Warfare Section. Report on Hitler, 1945 (Box 13B (7-Nazi and anti-Nazi propaganda), Folder 62)
  - Allied Forces Information Control Division. Intelligence Reports, 1945 July 28-1945 November 10 (Box 13B (7-Nazi and anti-Nazi propaganda), Folder 63)
  - Allied Forces Information Control Division. Intelligence Reports, 1946 January 28-1946 March 19 (Box 13B (7-Nazi and anti-Nazi propaganda), Folder 64)
  - War Office memoranda, 1940-1948 (Box 13B (7-Nazi and anti-Nazi propaganda), Folder 65)
- Notes and materials on various topics, 8; 70 file folders
  This series consists of materials collected by Hans Speier for his writing, course lectures, and topics of general interest.
  - Notebook 1 (loose leaf note pages): Population notes, Undated (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 1)
  - Notebook 2 (loose leaf note pages): "Literaturwissenssoziologie", Undated (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 2)
  - Notebook 3 (loose leaf note pages): Social stratification, Undated (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 3)
  - Notebook 4 (loose leaf note pages): Courage/heroism, Undated (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 4)
  - Adenauer, Konrad, Undated (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 5)
    Notes, clippings.
  - Berlin, Undated (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 6)
  - Book notes, Undated (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 7-8)
    Early typescript and handwritten notes on books.
  - Censorship, Undated (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 9)
  - Center for the Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences. Membership lists, Undated (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 10)
  - Communication, Undated (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 11)
    Notes.
  - Comparative Political Sociology. Lecture notes, Undated (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 12)
  - Conference Group on German Politics. Newsletter, 1977-1980 (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 13)
  - Conference on Weimar Germany, 1919-1932: Intellectuals, Culture and Politics. New School for Social Research, 1971 October 29-1971 October 30 (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 14)
    Conference materials.
  - Council on Foreign Relations, Study Group on Foreign Policy, 1964-1965 (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 15)
  - DeGaulle, Charles, Undated (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 16)
  - Department of State (U.S.). Press releases, 1960s (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 17)
  - Disarmament, Undated (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 18)
  - Distrust, Undated (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 19)
    Notes, typescripts.
  - Divided Germany (Berlin), Undated; clippings (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 20)
  - East German Intellectuals, Undated (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 21)
  - "Elite", Undated (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 22)
  - Emigration, 1933-1945; clippings (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 23)
  - Force and Diplomacy, Undated (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 24)
  - Friendship, Undated (Box 14 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 25)
  - German foreign policy, ca. 1967 (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 1)
  - Germany and the Great Powers, Undated (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 2)
  - Grimmelshausen, Undated (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 3)
  - Hallstein Doctrine, Undated; typescripts, notes (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 4)
  - Hearings, U.S. Senate publications, 1951-1971 (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 5)
    Most with annotations by Speier.
  - Heroism/Courage, Undated (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 6)
  - Historical perspectives, Undated; clippings (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 7)
  - History of War, Undated (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 8)
  - Humor, Undated (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 9)
  - Hungary, Undated; typescripts (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 10)
  - Internationale Wehrkunde-Begegnungen, 1966-1968 (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 11)
  - Jünger, Ernst, 1946-1947 (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 12)
  - July 20th 1944 Revolt, Undated (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 13)
  - Kennan, George F., Undated; clippings, notes, typescripts (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 14)
  - "Krise und Krisenbewusstsein", Undated (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 15)
  - Language/political communication, Undated (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 16)
  - Lederer, Emil, Undated (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 17)
    Notes, texts by Lederer (mostly photocopies).
  - Leites, Nathan, Undated (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 18)
  - Lepsius, M. Rainer, Undated; photocopies of texts (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 19)
  - "Limited War", Undated (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 20)
  - "Limited War", Undated; clippings (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 21)
  - Literature in the Middle Ages, Undated; clippings, notes, typescripts (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 22)
  - Middle Ages, Undated (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 23)
  - Middle East, 1965; clippings (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 24)
  - Military government of Germany, 1945-1947 (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 25)
  - Military strategy/tactics, Undated (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 26)
  - NATO, Undated (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 27)
  - Near East Crisis, Undated (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 28)
  - New School for Social Research, Undated; clippings, materials (Box 15 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 29)
  - Non-proliferation / Atomic weapons, Undated; clippings, typescripts, notes (Box 16 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 1)
  - Non-proliferation Treaty, 1967-1968; clippings (Box 16 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 2)
  - Peace, Nature of, Undated (Box 16 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 3)
  - Poland, Undated; clippings (Box 16 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 4)
  - Propaganda, Undated; clippings, notes (Box 16 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 5)
  - Public Opinion and Propaganda, Undated (Box 16 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 6)
  - Reunification, Undated (Box 16 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 7)
  - Social stratification, ca. 1941 (Box 16 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 8)
  - Sociology of Knowledge. Lecture notes, materials, Undated (Box 16 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 9)
  - Soviet Union, Undated; clippings, notes (Box 16 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 10)
  - Stark, Werner. Articles pertaining to, Undated (Box 16 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 11)
  - U.S. Foreign policy, Undated (Box 16 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 12)
    Notes, clippings, typescripts.
  - War / "Kriege", Undated (Box 16 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 13)
  - War Communications, Undated (Box 16 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, Undated (Box 16 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous notes and typescript pages, Undated (Box 16 (8-Notes and materials on various topics), Folder 16)
- Note cards in note card boxes, 9; 4 card files
  This series consists of 3 card files on "elite" personalities and books dealing with elite topics. The fourth card file contains cards arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Elites A - I, Undated (Box 17 (9-Note cards in note card boxes), Folder 1)
  - Elites J - Pe, Undated (Box 17 (9-Note cards in note card boxes), Folder 2)
  - Elites Pf - Z, Undated (Box 18 (9-Note cards in note card boxes), Folder 1)
  - Subjects, Undated (Box 18 (9-Note cards in note card boxes), Folder 2)
- Pamphlets, 1895-1970; 10; 47 file folders
  Arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Konferenz der Nichtkernwaffenstaaten. 29. August bis 28. September 1968 in Genf. Dokumentation über den deutschen Beitrag, 1968 November (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 1)
  - Die Lage der Vertriebenen und das Verhältnis des deutschen Volkes zu seinen östlichen Nachbarn, 1965 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 2)
  - Proposal for No First Use of Nuclear Weapons. Pros and Cons. Four Essays, 1963 September 15 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 3)
  - Wer will unter die Soldaten?, Undated (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 4)
  - Zehn Jahre im Dienst einer Gesinnung, im Kampf für Frieden, Freiheit, Kultur und Recht, Undated (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 5)
  - Ahmed, M. Samir. The Neutrals and the Test Ban Negotiations: An Analysis of the Non-aligned States' Efforts between 1962-1963, 1967 February (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 6)
  - American Enterprise Association. Special Analysis. The Berlin Crisis. Part I: Background, 1961 September 15 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 7)
  - American Institute of Public Opinion. The New Science of Public Measurement, Undated; 1938 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 8)
  - Burns, Arthur Lee. The Rationale of Catalytic War, 1959 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 9)
  - Conquest, Robert. After the Fall: Some Lessons, 1965 January-1965 February (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 10)
  - Dalton, Hugh. Government's Air Muddle Exposed, 1938 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 11)
  - Decter, Moshe (ed.). A Hero for Our Time. The Trial and Fate of Boris Kochubiyevsky, 1970 April (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 12)
  - Decter, Moshe (ed.). Redemption! Redemption! Redemption! Jewish Freedom Letters from Russia, 1970 May (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 13)
  - Gordon, Louis. The White Collar Workers Organize, 1938 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 14)
  - Gosnell, Harold F. Obstacles to Domestic Pamphleteering By OWI in World War II, 1946 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 15)
  - Homar, Helmuth. Konrad Adenauer. Bilder und Daten zum 80. Geburtstag, Undated (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 16)
  - International Student Service. Crisis, ca. 1934 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 17)
  - Jackson, Robert H. Grundlegende Rede vorgetragen im Namen der Vereinigten Staaten von Amerika, 1946 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 18)
  - Jaksch, Wendel. Germany and Eastern Europe. Two Documents of the Third German Bundestag 1961, Undated (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 19)
  - Kennedy, John F. Ich bin ein Berliner. John F. Kennedy in der deutschen Hauptstadt am 26. Juni 1963, Undated (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 20)
  - Krafft, Rudolf. Glänzendes Elend. Eine offene Kritik der Verhältnisse unseres Offizierkorps, 1895 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 21)
  - Kris, Ernst. Ego Development and the Comic, 1938 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 22)
  - Kris, Ernst. The Psychology of Caricature, 1936 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 23)
  - Lenin, N. Staat und Revolution. Incomplete copy, with numerous notations by Speier, Undated (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 24)
  - Molotov, Vyacheslav Mikhaylovich. Die Rede Molotows auf der Genfer Außenministerkonferenz am 8. November 1955, 1956 January (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 25)
  - Mosely, Philip E. and Marshall Shulman. The Changing Soviet Challenge, 1964 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 26)
  - Nasser, President Gamal Abdel. Address at the Palestine National Congress, 1965 May 31 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 27)
  - Plenge, Johann. Über den politischen Wert des Judentums, 1920 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 28)
  - The President's Science Advisory Committee. Scientific Progress, The Universities, and the Federal Government, 1960 November 15 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 29)
  - Rosinski, Herbert. The Reichswehr Today, 1939 April (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 30)
  - Rustow, Dankwart A. The Appeal of Communism to Islamic Peoples, 1965 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 31)
  - Schmitt, H. / Dr. Ehardt. Grundlegende Reden zum Gesetz zur Befreiung von Nationalsozialismus und Militarismus, 1946 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 32)
  - Schumacher, Kurt. Für Frieden, Freiheit, und Sozialismus, 1946 January 12 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 33)
  - Schumpeter, [Joseph A.]. Ökonomie und Psychologie des Unternehmers, 1929 May 22 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 34)
  - Seiler, Hans Gottlob. Die Masse bei Tacitus, 1936 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 35)
  - Siemsen, Anna. Politische Kunst und Kunstpolitik, 1927 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 36)
  - Sombart, Werner. Die Ordnung des Wirtschaftslebens, 1925 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 37)
  - Sombart, Werner. Weltanschauung, Wissenschaft und Wirtschaft, 1938 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 38)
  - Spence, J. E. / Thomas, Elizabeth. South Africa's Defense, 1966 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 39)
  - Undated (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 40)
    Stalin, J. W. "Über dialektischen und historischen Materialismus" (1945). Strölin, Karl. "Verräter oder Patrioten" (1952).
  - Strölin, Karl. Verräter oder Patrioten (1952).Strölin, Karl. Verräter oder Patrioten (1952), Undated (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 41)
    Strölin, Karl. "Verräter oder Patrioten" (1952). Strölin, Karl. "Verräter oder Patrioten" (1952).
  - U.S. Department of State. Berlin -- 1961, 1961 August (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 42)
  - U.S. Department of State. Directive Regarding the Military Government of Germany, 1947 July 11 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 43)
  - U.S. Department of State. The Soviet Note on Berlin: An Analysis, 1959 January (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 44)
  - Vorstand des deutschen Gewerkschaftsbundes. Mitverantwortung. Untersuchungen zur Frage des Wehrbeitrages, ca. 1952 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 45)
  - Wright, Quincy. On Predicting International Relations, the Year 2000, 1969-1970 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 46)
  - Zedler, John N. The Multilateral Force: A Misreading of German Aspirations, 1968 (Box 19 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 47)